<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table, by David &#34;Yoric&#34; Teller</title>
    <link>https://yoric.github.io/tags/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table, by David &#34;Yoric&#34; Teller</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 16:33:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://yoric.github.io/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>yoric.steps.next()</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/yoric-step-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 16:33:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/yoric-step-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The web is getting darker. It is being weaponized by trolls, bullies and bad actors and, as we&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed, this can have extremely grave consequences for individuals, groups, sometimes entire countries. So far, most of the counter-measures proposed by either governments or private actors are even scarier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The creators of the Matrix protocol have recently published &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.org/blog/2020/10/19/combating-abuse-in-matrix-without-backdoors&#34;&gt;the most promising plan I have seen&lt;/a&gt;. One that I believe stands a chance of making real headway in this fight, while respecting openness, decentralization, open-source and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been offered the opportunity to work on this plan. For this reason, after 9 years as an employee at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mozilla.org&#34;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving to &lt;a href=&#34;https://element.io&#34;&gt;Element&lt;/a&gt;, where I&amp;rsquo;ll try and contribute to making the web a better place. My last day at Mozilla will be October 30th.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Gitalk</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/switching-to-gitalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 11:58:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/switching-to-gitalk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Until now, this blog has been using Disqus as a comment mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While it is very useful, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to switch to a less invasive (and I believe more privacy-safe): gitalk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve left Disqus on in the pages on which users had already left comments. For other pages, Disqus is now deactivated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
