<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dsl on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</title>
    <link>https://yoric.github.io/tags/dsl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dsl on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 08:50:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yoric.github.io/tags/dsl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinkerbell Postmortem/Brain dump</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/thinkerbell-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 08:50:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/thinkerbell-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I was working on a research project called &amp;ldquo;Project Link&amp;rdquo; as part of
the Connected Devices branch of Mozilla. While this branch has since been stopped,
some part of Project Link lives on as &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2018/02/06/announcing-project-things-open-framework-connecting-devices-web/&#34;&gt;Project Things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the parts of Project Link that hasn&amp;rsquo;t made it to Project Things (so far)
was Thinkerbell: a Domain-Specific Language designed to let users program their SmartHome
without coding. While only parts of Thinkerbell were ever implemented, they were sufficient
to write programs such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I press any button labelled &amp;ldquo;light&amp;rdquo; in the living room, toggle all the lights in the living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the entry door is locked and the motion detector notices motion, send an alarm to my SmartPhone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinkerbell also had:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;semantics that ensured that scripts could continue/resume running unmonitored even when hardware
was replaced/upgraded/moved around the house, including both the server and the sensors;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a visual syntax, rather than a text syntax;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a novel type system designed to avoid physical accidents;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a semantics based on process algebras.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, I&amp;rsquo;d like to take the time to write a research paper on Thinkerbell, but
realistically, there is very little chance that I&amp;rsquo;ll find that time.
So, rather than letting these ideas die in some corner of my brain, here is a post-mortem
for Thinkerbell, in the hope that someone, somewhere, will pick some of the stuff and gives
it a second life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that some of the ideas exposed here were never actually implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>