<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Lighthouse on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</title>
    <link>https://yoric.github.io/categories/project-lighthouse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project Lighthouse on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:10:34 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yoric.github.io/categories/project-lighthouse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Things to do before you[r project] die[s]</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/how-to-survive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:10:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/how-to-survive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that all projects die, eventually, and that most projects die
before they have had a chance to have any impact. This is true of personal projects,
of open-source projects, of startup projects, of hardware projects, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Connected_Devices/Projects/Project_Lighthouse&#34;&gt;the IoT project on which I was working&lt;/a&gt;
did just that. It was funded, it was open-source, it was open-hardware, and it
still died before having the opportunity to release anything useful. In our case,
we got pretty far, didn&amp;rsquo;t run out of funds, and were a little polish away from
putting our first alpha-testers in front of a pretty advanced prototype before
a higher-level strategy pivot killed a number of projects at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, well, risks of the trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, working on it, we managed to learn or come up with a few tricks
to increase the chances of surviving at least long enough to release a product.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try to summarize and explain some of these tricks here. Hopefully, if you
have a project, regardless of funding and medium, you may find some of this
summary useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>