<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jit on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</title>
    <link>https://yoric.github.io/tags/jit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jit on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 15:51:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://yoric.github.io/tags/jit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coding for a Finite World</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/coding-for-a-finite-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 15:51:13 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/coding-for-a-finite-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(This is meant to be the first entry of a series which will cover individual points more in depth. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re the tech industry. We have ideas. We have ideas &lt;em&gt;all the time&lt;/em&gt;. And we&amp;rsquo;re used to turn our ideas into applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, how does it go&amp;hellip; here&amp;rsquo;s the back-end component&amp;hellip; here&amp;rsquo;s the front-end component. We&amp;rsquo;ll write the former in Python, or perhaps JavaScript, to optimize for prototyping. After all, we have &lt;em&gt;so many&lt;/em&gt; ideas, we need the ability to iterate quickly. Sprinkle in a few dependencies, that will speed us up. Oh, and let&amp;rsquo;s use ChatGPT and Copilot, we&amp;rsquo;ll be even faster. Oh, and performance, yeah, performance: microservices, Kafka, Redis, Kubernetes&amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;re now ready to scale up. Oh, Sentry, Prometheus and Grafana, too, where would we be without &amp;rsquo;em? For the front-end, we&amp;rsquo;ll write a website, and for mobile, Electron.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oh, wait a second, we need to make money and to fidelize our users! Let me see&amp;hellip; ads, tracking, and good reasons to revisit our app, perhaps a little NFT here, gamification&amp;hellip; alright, we should be good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three&amp;hellip; two&amp;hellip; one&amp;hellip; and we have shipped v1!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, the world is burning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s time we revisited how we do things?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HolyJIT: Could we write a multi-staged JIT compiler?</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/holyjit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 07:33:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/holyjit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m the author of this blog post, 99% of the work was done by Nicolas B. Pierron.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, my role in this project has largely been to play the wise old advisor,&#xA;nodding and smiling mischeviously whenever Nicolas started exploring new ideas,&#xA;and emitting cryptic comments in Reverse Jedi Notation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, we published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/javascript/2017/10/20/holyjit-a-new-hope/&#34;&gt;short (and mysterious) blog post&lt;/a&gt; in which we&#xA;mentioned HolyJIT, an early research project towards a novel approach to writing JITs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I would like to detail a bit more the ideas behind HolyJIT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
