<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>decentralization on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</title>
    <link>https://yoric.github.io/tags/decentralization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in decentralization on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 07:43:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yoric.github.io/tags/decentralization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moderated Federated Networks might actually be what we need - part 1</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/federated-moderation-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 07:43:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/federated-moderation-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the many &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt; moments of this ending year 2022, we have had the chance of
seeing the Twitter/Musk experiment unfold. I won&amp;rsquo;t spend time rehashing the many twists
of this experiment, just a moment to offer the best wishes to all who work or worked at
Twitter, in particular those being offered as scapegoats for the many sins of the C-suit,
both past and present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m going to spend time on is moderation. If we listen to the official discourse, this
entire Twitter/Musk experiment is about moderation. Also, as a direct consequence of aid
experiment, the number of users on Federated Networks such as Matrix and Mastodon has never
been so high. And Twitter, both past and present, has been a permanent demonstration that
moderation is hard. So&amp;hellip; what does it change to moderate a Federated Network?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert: it&amp;rsquo;s harder, but not impossible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
