<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yoric on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</title>
    <link>https://yoric.github.io/tags/yoric/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yoric on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 16:06:26 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yoric.github.io/tags/yoric/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 16:06:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Yoric, aka David Teller, I&amp;rsquo;m a Jack of all Threads at Element (aka Tech Lead). When I&amp;rsquo;m not producing code, I&amp;rsquo;m coordinating efforts within my team or between teams.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been spotted spending time on
mentoring junior developers and open-source contributors; federated/decentralized communication networks; protecting users making the Firefox web browser safer and faster; the Rust compiler and standard library; the SpiderMonkey JavaScript Virtual Machine; a micro-kernel; a next-gen browser engine; a few compilers; static analyzers; a few eBook readers; a programming language designed for multi-tiered web applications and services whose components distrust each other; a programming language designed for always-on, fault-tolerant, reboot-tolerant, hardware-replacement-tolerant, power-limited IoT applications; IoT for the disabled; IoT snooping countermeasure experiment; pedagogic robots; university teaching; high-school teaching; academic research; also, backpacking through exotic countries; &amp;hellip; You can find my latest resume here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
