<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</title>
    <link>https://yoric.github.io/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 10:09:36 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yoric.github.io/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Did Mozilla Remove XUL Add-ons?</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/why-did-mozilla-remove-xul-addons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 10:09:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/why-did-mozilla-remove-xul-addons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the past few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been chatting with Firefox users, trying to separate fact from rumor regarding the consequences of the August 2020 Mozilla layoffs. One of the topics that came back a few times was the removal of XUL-based add-ons during the move to Firefox Quantum. I was very surprised to see that, years after it happened, some community members still felt hurt by this choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, as someone pointed out on reddit, I realized that we still haven&amp;rsquo;t taken the time to explain in-depth why we &lt;em&gt;had no choice&lt;/em&gt; but to remove XUL-based add-ons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you&amp;rsquo;re ready for a dive into some of the internals of add-ons and Gecko, I&amp;rsquo;d like to take this opportunity to try and give you a bit more detail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HolyJIT: Could we write a multi-staged JIT compiler?</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/holyjit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 07:33:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/holyjit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m the author of this blog post, 99% of the work was done by Nicolas B. Pierron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, my role in this project has largely been to play the wise old advisor,
nodding and smiling mischeviously whenever Nicolas started exploring new ideas,
and emitting cryptic comments in Reverse Jedi Notation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, we published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/javascript/2017/10/20/holyjit-a-new-hope/&#34;&gt;short (and mysterious) blog post&lt;/a&gt; in which we
mentioned HolyJIT, an early research project towards a novel approach to writing JITs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I would like to detail a bit more the ideas behind HolyJIT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Binary AST diaries - How to replace proving with validating for fun and profit</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/binary-ast-pcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 10:44:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/binary-ast-pcc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this entry, I’d like to discuss one of the most interesting and unusual aspects of the Binary AST: how we gain performance by turning &lt;em&gt;proof-building&lt;/em&gt; into &lt;em&gt;validation&lt;/em&gt;, and why this is very good news for performance (and maybe not so good news for file size).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary AST - Motivations and Design Decisions - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/binary-ast-motivations-design-decisions-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 23:31:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/binary-ast-motivations-design-decisions-1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The key to making programs fast is to make them do practically nothing.&amp;rdquo; - Mike Haertel, creator of GNU Grep.
Binary AST - &amp;ldquo;Binary Abstract Syntax Tree&amp;rdquo; - is Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s proposal for specifying a binary-encoded syntax for JS with the intent of allowing browsers and other JS-executing environments to parse and load code as much as 80% faster than standard minified JS.
It has recently cleared Stage 1 of the TC39 standards process, and while the final byte-level format isn&amp;rsquo;t completely nailed down, we&amp;rsquo;re confident that the final implementation will deliver the impressive performance improvements promised by the prototype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Binary AST Engineering Newsletter #1</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/binary-ast-engineering-newsletter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 13:46:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/binary-ast-engineering-newsletter-1/</guid>
      <description>Hey, all cool kids have exciting Engineering Newsletters these days, so it&amp;rsquo;s high time the JavaScript Binary AST got one!
Summary JavaScript Binary AST is a joint project between Mozilla and Facebook to rethink how JavaScript source code is stored/transmitted/parsed. We expect that this project will help visibly speed up the loading of large codebases of JS applications and will have a large impact on the JS development community, including both web developers, Node developers, add-on developers and ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a JavaScript Binary AST</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/binary-ast-newsletter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 23:31:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/binary-ast-newsletter-1/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I would like to introduce the JavaScript Binary AST, an ongoing project that we hope will help make webpages load faster, along with a number of other benefits.
A little background Over the years, JavaScript has grown from one of the slowest scripting languages available to a high-performance powerhouse, fast enough that it can run desktop, server, mobile and even embedded applications, whether through web browsers or other environments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>