<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hobbies on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</title>
    <link>https://yoric.github.io/categories/hobbies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hobbies on Il y a du thé renversé au bord de la table !</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 19:28:07 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yoric.github.io/categories/hobbies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Is there an afterlife? (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 19:28:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s simple, really: every question has an answer, and somewhere in Space·Time, there is someone who has that answer. Do you want that answer? Do you want it? Well, &lt;strong&gt;Time Will Tell, Inc.&lt;/strong&gt; can get it. Sign up with us, and we&amp;rsquo;ll send a team of highly trained Space·Time operatives after that very special person who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Is there an afterlife?</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 19:24:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is there an afterlife?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, of course, there is, and you came to the right place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: The Time Adjustment Foundation</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-time-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 12:21:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-time-adjustment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the Time Federation is forever limited by its Prime Directive, some wanted to go further, and managed to create a covert operations branch called the &lt;strong&gt;Time Adjustment Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;. And further is exactly where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: The Time Federation</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-time-federation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:40:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-time-federation/</guid>
      <description>After the debacle of the Space·Time Fleet and the loss of many of its Continuum Indirections to imploded Pocket Continuums, the idea of a large Space·Time force was very nearly shelved, and its remaining ships docked. Some of the surviving cadres of the Space·Time Fleet, however, took advantage of this lack of purpose, and came up with an idea to salvage some of the huge costs sunk into the fleet itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And now, for something completely different: Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:30:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yoric.github.io/post/rtb-about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m not busy attempting to reduce the startup time and power requirements of web pages with the JavaScript Binary AST, I&amp;rsquo;m into Improv Acting and Role-Playing Games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce a hobby project of mine, which I have started over the summer: Ronin Time Bureaucrats – an narrative/improv Role-Playing Game of Handwavy Time Paradoxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>